Mr. Saaheel Bhoopen Majethia - Sr. Lead Engineer

Website: http://www.smajethia.com

Objective

To implement my technical and management skills for the growth of the organization, and to improve knowledge base within my team through regular technical and non-technical training programs.

Summary

- Sr. Lead Engineer(Asst. Manager) at People Interactive Pvt. Ltd. with 10+ years of extensive experience with website frontend and backend development.
- Customer Focused and Results-oriented team player with excellent communication, and team management skills.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages	PHP, JavaScript, HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3
Web Frameworks	ReactJS w/ Redux, jQuery, Zend, Laravel, Lumen, CodeIgniter, YII
Web CMS	WordPress, Drupal, Magento
Databases	MySQL, NoSql (Redis, Memcache, MongoDb)
Other Tools	Git, AWS Services, XAMPP
External API	AWS Services, eBay API, Payment Gateway like Authorize.net, etc

Experience

People Interactive (I) Pvt. Ltd. (Shaadi.com) - Tardeo, Mumbai

Sr. Lead Engineer - (March 2014 – Feb 2019) - (**4 Years 11 Months**)

Responsibilities includes developing features, Discussion on Product spec and Architecture discussion, Timely Updates to Stakeholders, Work breakdown and Allocation, Code reviews, System monitoring and Project Status Reporting.

eTouch Systems Pvt Ltd. - Thane, Mumbai

Sr. Software Engineer - (September 2012 – March 2014) - (**1 Year 6 Months**)

Responsibilities included module development and maintenance for Client Portal, Creating document of modules developed.

Annet Technologies Pvt Ltd. - Mahalakshmi Mumbai

Technical Lead - (July 2010 – September 2012) - (2 Years 2 Months)

Responsibilities included website development, Client Interaction, Status updates with Client, Prioritizing task based on Client needs.

Pulse Solutions. - Goregaon Mumbai

PHP Developer - (April 2010 – June 2010) - (**3 Months**)

Responsibilities included website maintenance and bug fixes.

Infinitech Solution Pvt. Ltd. - Mulund Mumbai

Sr. Software Developer - (June 2008 – March 2010) - (**1 Year 9 Months**)

Responsibilities included website development, Client Interaction, System Design.

Projects

Company	People Interactive (I) Pvt Ltd (Shaadi.com)	
Company	People interactive (i) Pvt Ltd (Snaadi.com)	

1. Automating Photo Screening

This project was done to reduce the amount of time spent on manually screening each photo to ensure no pornography, celebrity or wrong gender photos were uploaded.

Responsibility Included:-

- Designing & Analysing Technical Architecture of the system
- Drafting Technical requirement and break down Business requirement for Vendors
- Team discussion and get Project updates from the external team.

Impact: Reduced time spent for Photo Screening by 40 man hours per day.

Tools: AWS Rekognition, Python SDK, PHP5.6.

2. Profile page & Search Pages in REACTJS w/ Redux

This migration project was done to implement new Material UI design with-in Profile & Search Listing pages using Frontend technologies from Zend Framework pages.

Responsibility Included:-

- Development of reusable components using TDD approach
- Using Storybook as the development tool for Product to integrate most of the business cases

Impact: User engagement on the site improved by ~10%

Tools: ReactJS w/ Redux, HTML5, CSS3, TDD using Jest & Enzyme

3. CRM Backend System

Automation of Profile Screening using Data Algorithms. This project was done to reduce the time in Profile screened and activated on the site.

Responsibility Included:-

• Development of new features to enable CRM team work efficiently

Impact: Reduced time spent by 100 man hours per day by automation for profile screening **Tools:** PHP5.4, MySQL, REDIS, Zend Framework, HTML, CSS.

4. Interactive Web Chat Client for Users

This project was done to implement new chat client on Web.

Responsibility Included:-

- Implementation of Business requirement
- Development of API's for Mobile clients
- Responsible for complete life cycle delivery and Business Impact using Storybook as the development tool for Product to integrate most of the business cases

Impact: User engagement on the site improved by ~20%

Tools: PHP5.4, MySQL, Strophe Javascript Client Library & OpenFire Chat Server, Memcache.

Company

eTouch Systems India Pvt Ltd

Migration of Multiple Intuit Blog in Single Installation of WP (Multi-Site) http://blog.intuit.com/

This project was done to combine multiple blogs of multiple products of Intuit in single WordPress Installation

Responsibility Included:-

- Modification in existing WP installation
- Implementation of JSON API for Mobile App
- Implementation of new widgets .

Impact: Reduced management overhead of multiple installation & cost of resources.

Tools: WordPress(3.5.2), HTML, CSS, PHP5, MySQL, jQuery.

2. Expert's Corner - Document Management System

This project was to analyse the current working of LMS developed. Create technical documentation , provide the recommendation for enhancing the system behaviour and performance.

Responsibility Included:-

- Reviewing the existing code and application functionality
- Designing Process Flow documentation
- Code and Database Optimization recommendation
- Working on bug fixing and enhancement as per client requirement

Impact: Get the complete process flow of the system streamlined to enhance operation

Impact: YII Framework, PHP5, MySQL, ExtJS 3.4, Ajax, HTML, CSS.

Company

Annet Technologies

Development of Corporate website for Aracon on WordPress http://www.araconfiber.com/

This project was implemented using WordPress, so the members of the company can edit necessary information.

Responsibility Included:-

- Analyzing the requirement & Work Breakdown
- Weekly Status Updates for Client reporting
- Plugins and Widget development in WordPress

Impact: Manage data on the website with instant modification as and when required.

Tools: WordPress 3.2.x, PHP5, MySQL, HTML, CSS, jQuery.

2. Integration of eBay store and Amazon store with Magento API

This project was done to create a central point of Magento store to connect with eBay & Amazon store to sell medicines.

Responsibility Included:-

- Analyzing the requirement
- R&D of using API for E-Commerce Platform
- Development of Product Upload Module
- Functional Testing of developed modules & Integrated System

Impact: Easy handling of inventory using single store and getting accurate inventory stats.

Tools: PHP5, MySQL, Javascript, Ajax, jQuery, Magento, eBay Store API, Amazon Store API.

Company

Infinitech Solutions

1. eGuardian - School Management System

This product was designed to provide complete School Management System along with sending SMS alerts to Parents, Wireless Attendance via High frequency RFID, etc

Responsibility Included:-

- Analyzing the Business requirement and R&D for available tools
- Assigning and breakdown of work with team members
- Implementation of Course and Fees module
- Functional Testing of developed modules & Integrated System

Impact: Reduce manual overhead of marking attendance and send timely alert about current location of the child like in / out / travel, etc.

Tools: PHP5, MySQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Ajax.

Education

PG Diploma in Management - Distance (eBusiness)

From: Welingkar Institute of Management Development & Research, Mumbai

Year: 2015

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics

From: Shah & Anchor Kutchhi Engineering College, Chembur(E)

Year: 2007, Cleared with First Class - 63.65%

HSC(12th)

From: Shree S.K. Somaiya College, Mumbai State Board

Year: 2003, Cleared with First Class - 74.50%

SSC(10th)

From: Model English School, Mumbai State Board **Year:** 2001, Cleared with First Class - 74.13%

Co-Curricular Activities

- Attended "React Foo" Mumbai & Delhi 2018
- Organized "WordCamp" Mumbai 2016, 2017 & 2018
- Attended "Drupal CAMP" Mumbai 2014, Mumbai 2018
- Attended "WordCamp" Pune 2013,2015,2017,2019 and Baroda 2014
- Member of "Annet Staff Welfare Committee" Organizing various events for Staff

Interests

Listening to old classical music & Photography